<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trevor Arjeski's Site</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Trevor Arjeski's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Trevor Arjeski</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 19:33:07 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trevarj.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Late Start in Computer Programming</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/advice2noob/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 19:33:07 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/advice2noob/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving advice (sometimes unsolicited) to people who want to shift into computer programming as a career.
Being a late bloomer in programming is definitely manageable, but I believe it requires careful planning and a specific behavior.
Overview This has been beaten like a dead horse by #learn2code tweets and Youtube videos, but these are the two main goals to become a general application programmer:
Learn the fundamentals of programming and the basics of how a computer works Learn one programming language and write programs in it Contribute to open source projects and/or have a personal project Behavior The most difficult undertaking and, what I think, is the most important factor for learning programming is the obsession needed to succeed.</description></item><item><title>Ten Years a Dev</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/ten_years/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/ten_years/</guid><description>Introduction This year will mark my tenth year working as a professional software engineer. Lately, I have been contemplating on my experience and my next steps and goals that I would like to achieve as a programmer. I also want to be sure that I don&amp;#39;t fall into the same traps as I did before.
This post is intended as notes for my future-self. Hopefully this will help me organize my thoughts on what to do in the next ten years.</description></item><item><title>Mentorship</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/mentorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/mentorship/</guid><description>The most valuable thing I got out of my first job was that I was being mentored by a senior guy - something I feel like will never come my way again unless someone is willing to mentor a doofus in his thirties with ten years of experience. He wasn&amp;#39;t a modern &amp;#34;senior&amp;#34; engineer who has five years of experience either. He had about 30+ years of experience under his belt.</description></item><item><title>The If-Else Programmer</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/if_else/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/if_else/</guid><description>I had a half-joke where I would tell people that all I did at a previous job was write if-else statements to fix every problem that came up. There are two reasons why I evolved into the if-else programmer:
Ideas and creativity were ignored. Anything a developer offered to improve the code was rejected and deemed as not needed by management. The value was only found in things that instantly settled client demands.</description></item><item><title>Test Post</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/test_post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 22:13:26 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/test_post/</guid><description>This is a Test Test text
A reminder how to create new posts From root of the project, run:
$ hugo new posts/[title].md</description></item><item><title/><link>https://trevarj.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/about/</guid><description>I have 10 years of professional development experience (as of 2023).
My technological interests include: FOSS, Linux, Unix tools / philosophy, various programming languages, text editors, tinkering.
Favorite programming languages:
C (best overall) Rust (best strongly typed) Haskell (best purely functional) Current technical aspirations:
Make a commit to a Unix-like operating system Work full-time on open source software Be a maintainer of a large open source project</description></item></channel></rss>