<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>trev's website</title>
<description></description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://trevarj.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>A Late Start in Computer Programming</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/advice2noob.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/advice2noob.html</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 19:33:07 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">A Late Start in Computer Programming</h1><a id="user-content-a-late-start-in-computer-programming" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: A Late Start in Computer Programming" href="#a-late-start-in-computer-programming"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Recently I've been giving advice (sometimes unsolicited) to people who
want to shift into computer programming as a career.</p>
<p>Being a late bloomer in programming is definitely manageable, but I believe it
requires careful planning and a specific behavior.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Overview</h2><a id="user-content-overview" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Overview" href="#overview"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>This has been beaten like a dead horse by #learn2code tweets and Youtube
videos, but these are the main goals to become a general application
programmer:</p>
<ol>
<li>Learn the fundamentals of programming and the basics of how a computer works</li>
<li>Learn one programming language and write programs in it</li>
<li>Contribute to open source projects and/or have a personal project</li>
</ol>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Behavior</h2><a id="user-content-behavior" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Behavior" href="#behavior"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>The most difficult undertaking and, what I think, is the most important factor
for learning programming is the obsession needed to succeed. Unless you are a
gifted individual, you will need to really buckle down and grind. You don't
necessarily need to pull all-nighters like a college kid, but you need to have
a constant motivation to explore and learn about computers and programming.
Of course, this behavior is relative to how quickly you expect to get a
programming career. Less obsessed -&gt; longer until you secure a job.</p>
<p>Don't just click around the computer like an idiot, become a power user and
start <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Art_of_Unix_Programming" rel="nofollow">using Linux</a>
and crafting <a href="https://www.lazyvim.org/" rel="nofollow">your own development environment</a>.
Start living as a computer nerd even if your hobby is cooking breakfast foods
and grilling meats or something, forget it for a while. You have to adopt the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_culture#Programming" rel="nofollow">hacker culture</a>.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Fundamentals</h2><a id="user-content-fundamentals" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Fundamentals" href="#fundamentals"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>This is the stuff that people spend an undergrad in computer science learning:
data structures, algorithms, databases, operating systems, computer
architecture, etc. Unless you are going to actually get a degree and take these
courses, you will need to use <a href="https://github.com/ossu/computer-science">free and open
courses</a> to gather this knowledge.</p>
<p>Stay away from too many video tutorials. Read through course material and do
the homework and projects as if you were in a class. People love to skip over
all this "boring" stuff because it doesn't yield immediate results and, well,
feels like school. This will establish confidence and adaptability.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Writing Programs</h2><a id="user-content-writing-programs" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Writing Programs" href="#writing-programs"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Nowadays it's trendy to obsess over which programming language to learn and get
good at, but this is not something a noob dev needs to think about. The most
important thing is picking one programming language and writing programs in it
(obvious?). If you are concerned about the job hunt, it may be useful to go
to a job site and see what languages are being used at companies in your
area.</p>
<ol>
<li>Pick a language</li>
<li>Read the <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/" rel="nofollow">official docs</a> (or an esteemed
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structure_and_Interpretation_of_Computer_Programs" rel="nofollow">textbook</a>)</li>
<li>Use the language for the courses mentioned above (basics, data structures,
algorithms)</li>
<li>Solve <a href="https://adventofcode.com/" rel="nofollow">coding challenges</a>
</li>
<li>Write small programs (simple games, scripts, utilities, etc)</li>
</ol>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Open Source</h2><a id="user-content-open-source" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Open Source" href="#open-source"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>The single most important factor to securing a job, in my opinion, is having
open source contributions. For an employer, nothing screams "I CAN CODE AND I
LIKE IT!" louder than seeing evidence of you doing it for free and for your own
leisure. They must envision Jira tickets being closed faster than they can can
be created (with zero details or requirements).</p>
<p>After you've gotten comfortable in a programming language, you MUST find a
project written in that language and start diving into the code. Find software
that is useful to you, or something you find interesting. Read the
CONTRIBUTING.md and start tinkering or looking at issues and seeing if you can
be mentored into fixing or adding something. This will also teach the soft
skills of collaborating on software.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Personal Project</h2><a id="user-content-personal-project" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Personal Project" href="#personal-project"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>It's pretty obvious that you need a portfolio to look employable nowadays.
There's nothing better than having an open source project that you maintain and
improve. It's a plus if other people use it or contribute to it.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">The End</h1><a id="user-content-the-end" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: The End" href="#the-end"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>RSS/Atom Feed Reader in BASH!</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/Feed_Reader_in_BASH!.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/Feed_Reader_in_BASH!.html</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 23:21:40 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">RSS/Atom Feed Reader in BASH!</h1><a id="user-content-rssatom-feed-reader-in-bash" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: RSS/Atom Feed Reader in BASH!" href="#rssatom-feed-reader-in-bash"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I'm on a Bash spree <a href="./my_new_SSG_and_blog.html">lately</a>, or as some might say,
"going absolutely bonkers", "getting down with the sickness", "getting a few
screws knocked loose"...whichever you prefer. I just really had a craving for,
what I call, "the arts and crafts of programming", AKA gluing a bunch of
Unix/CLI tools together until you have something that kind of works. Imagine
sitting in an insane asylum all day and making <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macaroni_art" rel="nofollow">art from
macaroni</a>, but you connect the
macaroni (elbows) to each other so it forms a kind of pipe system. Or maybe you
remember <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uzx9ArZ7MUU" rel="nofollow">that screensaver</a> from
the 90's with the pipes -- that's basically writing Bash!</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Rationale</h2><a id="user-content-rationale" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Rationale" href="#rationale"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>None of that makes any sense, but all you need to know is that I really wanted
to read some RSS feeds and couldn't settle on a reader. They either seemed too
complicated or just a pain to learn. I had used some of the suckless ones. I
think <a href="https://github.com/skeeto/elfeed">elfeed</a> is really nice and used that
one for a while, even though I make fun of emacs all the time and don't even use
it as an editor. I was thinking about it and I was able to break down what I
needed into a few high level steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the feed files (XML)</li>
<li>Parse the XML</li>
<li>Store the parsed data</li>
<li>Display the necessary fields to the user</li>
<li>Have some minimal controls, like marking as read and opening in a browser</li>
</ol>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Getting to Work</h2><a id="user-content-getting-to-work" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Getting to Work" href="#getting-to-work"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Immediately, I knew I wanted to use <a href="https://github.com/junegunn/fzf">fzf</a> for
displaying and previewing the feed items, and providing some navigation and
controls. XML is really annoying to me and an unintuitive format for querying
data, in my opinion. This is why I decided quickly that I was going to write a
small tool to parse XML into JSON, using the Rust
<a href="https://crates.io/crates/rss" rel="nofollow"><code>rss</code></a>. It uses minimal libraries and was <a href="https://github.com/trevarj/rss2json">only
34 lines</a> to slap together. It was also
really easy to support Atom alongside RSS and just move them into JSON as soon
as possible. This will probably make the reader less accessible because now
people will need to install this unpopular tool I made, which isn't widely
available unless you have Rust installed.</p>
<p>With the feeds in a nice JSON format, I could use the powerful tool
<a href="https://github.com/jqlang/jq">jq</a> to not only extract what I needed, but to
chunk up the feed into individual files per feed item. This made it easy to just
store everything on the filesystem and avoid having to use a database. Each feed
has it's own folder with read/ and unread/ subfolders containing JSON files per
feed item. Upon startup <code>jq</code> will just parse all the .json files and feed the
data to <code>fzf</code>.</p>
<p>That's pretty much the interesting part. The rest is just configuration and
glue. It's better just to take a look at this demo:</p>
<p><a href="https://asciinema.org/a/656386" rel="nofollow"><img src="https://camo.githubusercontent.com/8e387ac362bbaf8b760dea7393988a5859feec089880b8fb5fb25d0a765ee338/68747470733a2f2f61736369696e656d612e6f72672f612f3635363338362e737667" alt="asciicast" data-canonical-src="https://asciinema.org/a/656386.svg" style="max-width: 100%;"/></a></p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Shortcomings</h2><a id="user-content-shortcomings" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Shortcomings" href="#shortcomings"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>After adding around 10 feeds with ~200 posts total, the performance is still
decent, but you can tell that it isn't as snappy as other readers. This could
probably be resolved with a sqlite database.</p>
<p>Another thing is the mechanism to load the posts. Right now, on startup the
feeds are asynchronously downloaded and the user has to manual refresh for them
to appear in the list. I'm not sure if there is a way to somehow "push" the
posts in using a pipe or something. I don't think there is a way for them to
maintain their order though, since <code>fzf</code> doesn't seem to have a way to keep
things sorted.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/trevarj/frdr">frdr (feed reader)</a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>Distro-Hopping from Arch to Gentoo</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/gentoo.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/gentoo.html</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:32:47 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">Distro-Hopping from Arch to Gentoo</h1><a id="user-content-distro-hopping-from-arch-to-gentoo" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Distro-Hopping from Arch to Gentoo" href="#distro-hopping-from-arch-to-gentoo"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>This past weekend (starting on a Thursday) I decided to scrap my Arch install
and install <a href="https://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Handbook:AMD64" rel="nofollow">Gentoo</a>. I suppose you
could say I fell for <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/install-gentoo" rel="nofollow">the old 4chan
meme</a>.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Distro-hopping History</h2><a id="user-content-distro-hopping-history" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Distro-hopping History" href="#distro-hopping-history"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Year</th>
<th/>
<th/>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>~2005</td>
<td>Ubuntu</td>
<td>Installed on old laptop from a disc I got in a PC Magazine. Smashed the wifi card into the motherboard and that was the end of that install</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2010</td>
<td>Ubuntu</td>
<td>On Macbook. This is how I learned to program in a Linux environment</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2012</td>
<td>Crunchbang</td>
<td>Deleted Windows for a bit to learn Linux better</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2013</td>
<td>Arch</td>
<td>Started "ricing" on the Macbook</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2019</td>
<td>Manjaro</td>
<td>KDE + Linux Gaming (daily driving Linux)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2020</td>
<td>PopOS</td>
<td>Searching for better desktop/Nvidia experience</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2021-2024</td>
<td>Arch/Artix</td>
<td>Using Ubuntu full-time at work</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Apr 2024</td>
<td>Gentoo</td>
<td/>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Arch has probably been the best distro I've experienced. I don't really need to
explain all its benefits since they have all been answered elsewhere online. For
me it was a great balance between customization, productivity and minimalism.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Why not $DISTRO_NAME?</h2><a id="user-content-why-not-distro_name" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Why not $DISTRO_NAME?" href="#why-not-distro_name"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Thanks to the <a href="https://systemcrafters.net" rel="nofollow">System Crafter's IRC</a> channel, when
everyone was discussing distros to try or ones that they use, I began
contemplating (again) what my perfect distro would be.</p>
<p>The answer that I always land on is not Gentoo -- it's a BSD. After some time
experimenting with FreeBSD, I really enjoyed the ecosystem and documentation
that they had. It does come with a few quirks that I can't come to terms with,
like having to use Linux emulation for some programs. It always seems possible
to use it full-time but then a program sneaks up on you that only works under
Linux. Perhaps once my Nvidia hardware dies then I will try out FreeBSD or
OpenBSD again.</p>
<p>So, for GNU/Linux distributions, it came down to Artix vs Void vs Gentoo.
Switching to Artix, something I've done before, would be trivial.</p>
<p>I spent a day looking into Void and experimenting in a VM, but I didn't really
find it to be any better than Arch/Artix or have something beneficial that it
could sell me. Unless the system has something drastically different to
offer, like Nix/Guix (and I don't need extreme reproducibility), then it just seems
not worth the time investment.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Gentoo Linux</h2><a id="user-content-gentoo-linux" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Gentoo Linux" href="#gentoo-linux"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Gentoo seems to tick a lot of boxes for me:</p>
<ul>
<li>[x] Control</li>
<li>[x] Customizability</li>
<li>[x] Ability to be minimalist (sometimes forced, if you don't want to compile!)</li>
<li>[x] Large, knowledgeable community to learn from (forum, IRC)</li>
<li>[x] Great documentation (handbook, wiki)</li>
</ul>
<p>At first, I was intimidated and irritated at the complexity, but the more I read
the more I was convinced this is a great distro. Things started to make sense
and I was actually learning and re-learning more about a GNU/Linux system under
the hood.</p>
<p>It only took me a couple days (without full attention) to get up and running
back to where I was with Arch. I utilized a few binary packages for large,
compile intensive programs, like Firefox and a kernel.</p>
<p>Compiling everything might deter a lot of people, but for me it is a way to be
conscious of what I am installing and how to maintain a system that isn't full
of random packages. If I see that the dependency list of a package is much too
large, I'll reconsider using that package and look for an alternative. It was
annoying when I wanted to install <code>shellcheck</code> and saw how many Haskell
dependencies it uses. I ended up installing the binary for it, which I was
thankful existed.</p>
<p>I still need some time to adjust to the utilities for maintaining a Gentoo
system, so I can't really speak about much more yet.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Will I Hop Again?</h2><a id="user-content-will-i-hop-again" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Will I Hop Again?" href="#will-i-hop-again"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Like a lot of people, I tend to go through tech phases. Eventually, I may just
get tired of compiling stuff, especially if the time comes when I don't have a
separate PC for work and have to quickly install some tools to be productive.</p>
<p>As I said before, I'd still like to try to work towards daily driving a BSD.
There is also the possibility of looking for an even more hardcore Linux distro
like LFS in order to really learn a system in and out. I could even take a
completely different direction and install Debian and then manually compile
fresh versions of programs that I frequently use.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>The If-Else Programmer</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/if_else.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/if_else.html</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">The If-Else Programmer</h1><a id="user-content-the-if-else-programmer" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: The If-Else Programmer" href="#the-if-else-programmer"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I had a half-joke where I would tell people that all I did at a previous job was
write if-else statements to fix every problem that came up. There are two
reasons why I evolved into the if-else programmer:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Ideas and creativity were ignored. Anything a developer offered to improve the
code was rejected and deemed as not needed by management. The value was only
found in things that instantly settled client demands.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sometimes all you can do with fragile, legacy, test-less (good luck
refactoring), spaghetti code is add +meatballs+ if-statements to check for
null or some condition that was found on a production system and needed a
hotfix. You'll be faced with no choice but to fix every problem with
band-aids.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Even if I was closing a bunch of tickets, it was mind-numbing and made me not
enjoy programming, which resulted in my skills stagnating during the workday and
then fading away since I didn't program in my free time.</p>
<p>It was easy for me to get into this situation and then held hostage by a nice
paycheck and various psychological reasons. Minus the dire circumstances, I
believe it is a good time to move on when you become an if-else programmer
instead of risking your skills and falling behind for a (temporary) job.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>Learning Guile for Spring Lisp Game Jam 2024</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/lisp_game_jam_2024.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/lisp_game_jam_2024.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 16:09:32 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">Learning Guile for Spring Lisp Game Jam 2024</h1><a id="user-content-learning-guile-for-spring-lisp-game-jam-2024" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Learning Guile for Spring Lisp Game Jam 2024" href="#learning-guile-for-spring-lisp-game-jam-2024"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Today I finished <a href="https://github.com/trevarj/gdotris">my entry</a> for the <a href="https://itch.io/jam/spring-lisp-game-jam-2024/entries" rel="nofollow">Spring
Lisp Game Jam 2024</a>. It's
nothing really special, just a conversion of my Tetris clone, dotris, written in
Guile Scheme.</p>
<p>I wanted to use the game jam to learn Guile while being held accountable for
actually doing something. I've been looking at Guile and reading the manual for
a few months, toying with simple scripts, and even taking an attempt at writing
a Guix System config (AND FAILING!). Converting my ncurses game written in C
over to Guile seemed doable in this timeframe.</p>
<p>I started off trying to write everything purely functional, and writing like I
would write Haskell, but that was short lived. After that I just starting doing
more "casual" programming where I just wanted to get the job done and have a
functional game. I would say the code ended up looking more like how I would
write Ocaml. I'm not actually sure if it resembles idiomatic Scheme at all!</p>
<p>After a few days, Guile became comfortable to work with and appears to be really
powerful. I haven't even scratched the surface on the powers of Scheme, but it
seems extremely flexible. Using the REPL was quite useful and more engaging than
writing boring unit tests. I'd like to become more proficient in REPL-driven
development and maybe find some resources on how to be productive with a
REPL. Right now, I can't really see how it would be used in a very large project
or whether it is actually faster than writing some unit tests. Some things were
irritating to me, coming from using a language like Rust daily, like no LSP
(Geiser is OK) and hardcore type system.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>Mentorship</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/mentorship.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/mentorship.html</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">Mentorship</h1><a id="user-content-mentorship" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Mentorship" href="#mentorship"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>The most valuable thing I got out of my first job was that I was being mentored
by a senior guy - something I feel like will never come my way again unless
someone is willing to mentor a doofus in his thirties with ten years of
experience. He wasn't a modern "senior" engineer who has five years of
experience either. He had about 30+ years of experience under his belt. It was
really helpful to have someone there to guide me in research and to discuss
things at length when I was stuck. I would much rather take a positive
mentorship than have an education budget that I can spend how I wish. "Make sure
you clear it with HR first haha."</p>
<p>From my observation it is becoming more and more uncommon to get mentored at a
job or even be able to discuss topics at length, but this may be my ignorant
perception now as a fully remote worker. I haven't heard first hand from anyone
about being mentored, and only have seen it mentioned rarely on a job
description.</p>
<p>Another thing I've noticed is how managers don't want to "waste" resources on
similar methods of knowledge sharing, like pair programming or shadowing. "Jump
right in and ask for help if you're stuck!"</p>
<p>It seems the industry is only concerned with hiring "self-starters" and people
who can grind without guidance, instead of properly on-boarding and mentoring a
person to fit in with the team and actually be successful and useful. The
companies seem to be focused only on finding these "10X-ers" who won't question
anything and can just churn out heaps of SLOC.</p>
<p>I don't think this is only a problem with junior devs. Why can't a thirty year
old doofus like me get mentored too? Is that just called "going back to get a
master's degree"? That does sound like an option, along with paid mentorships
that some Github celebrities offer.</p>
<p>One alternative is to find an open source project that is accepting
contributions, preferably one that you use and want to give back to. Start
putting up pull-requests on this project and give the maintainers a chance to
review them. There is a good chance that you will be provided a lot of helpful
feedback and guidance, perhaps even higher quality than someone at work will
give you. This has been beneficial to me, especially when the maintainer is
highly skilled and generous with his time.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>My New SSG and Blog</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/my_new_SSG_and_blog.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/my_new_SSG_and_blog.html</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 18:31:31 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">My New SSG and Blog</h1><a id="user-content-my-new-ssg-and-blog" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: My New SSG and Blog" href="#my-new-ssg-and-blog"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Welcome to my revamped blog that I made with my latest tinker project,
<a href="https://github.com/trevarj/poogo">poogo</a>.</p>
<p>Poogo is a static-site generator written in bash, which utilizes the <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/rest/markdown">Github
markdown API</a> to convert Markdown into
HTML.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Hugo -&gt; Poogo</h2><a id="user-content-hugo---poogo" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Hugo -&gt; Poogo" href="#hugo---poogo"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>With this I can say goodbye to <a href="https://gohugo.io/" rel="nofollow">Hugo</a> (<code>sudo emerge --unmerge hugo</code>) and stop complaining about how I don't want to learn Hugo
themes or figure out how to work it. I will say that Hugo is quite nice and
simple enough, but I don't even need such power for my blog that has zero
readers and is hosted on Github Pages. So, I finally convinced myself to
frantically slap together a single <code>bash(1)</code> script that can do everything I
need.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Requirements</h2><a id="user-content-requirements" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Requirements" href="#requirements"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I wanted to create a simple tool for a simple blog. Also, it's pretty fun to
push Unix tools to the limit and scour StackOverflow looking for the coolest
one-liners and tricks.</p>
<p>Here is what I needed:</p>
<ol>
<li>Take Markdown files and convert them to HTML</li>
<li>Ability to regenerate on new Markdown changes</li>
<li>Generate a RSS feed for all the posts</li>
<li>Minimal CSS that works with the generated HTML</li>
</ol>
<p>Solutions:</p>
<ol>
<li>Github's Markdown API to convert MD-&gt;HTML. Instead of using GH Pages built-in
MD-&gt;Jekyll, this allows me to be able to take my site anywhere else.</li>
<li>Bash <code>-ot / -nt</code> on files</li>
<li>Simple substitution stuff and inspiration from
<a href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/lb/blob/master/sup"><code>lb</code></a>
</li>
<li>A quick search for minimal CSS led me to <a href="https://github.com/kevquirk/simple.css">Simple
CSS</a>, and of course <a href="https://nordtheme.com" rel="nofollow">Nord color
palette</a>
</li>
</ol>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Reflections</h2><a id="user-content-reflections" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Reflections" href="#reflections"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I got to the MVP after only tinkering on and off for a few days. Basically using
shell-driven development (not as cool as a REPL, but pretty good!) and hacking
stuff together until it works. I am not super proud of the code itself, but I
didn't set out to write the most beautiful and robust bash SSG (one probably
exists).</p>
<p>It was really relaxing to not have to to care about code cleanliness or whether
or not someone else can read it. Just coding to get something done. Perhaps this
is a side effect of using a language that lets you bend the rules and do wacky
stuff.</p>
<p>There is also something satisfying about solving something using
a Unix Philosophy way instead of just installing some new tool and having to
learn the ecosystem. Spending time learning more <code>sed(1)</code> is pretty amazing,
even if it sometimes feels inelegant or the solution is cryptic at first glance.</p>
<p>Here's a weird <code>sed</code> line that I learned:</p>
<div class="highlight highlight-source-shell"><pre><span class="pl-c"><span class="pl-c">#</span> extract the "title" of a post for a HTML &lt;title&gt;, a markdown '#' header from a</span>
<span class="pl-c"><span class="pl-c">#</span> file, or fallback to the title found in the &lt;header&gt; markdown file</span>
<span class="pl-en">extract_title</span>() {
	s=<span class="pl-s"><span class="pl-pds">'</span>/# .*/{s/# (.*)/\1/p;Q};q1<span class="pl-pds">'</span></span> <span class="pl-c"><span class="pl-c">#</span> returns 1 on a non-match</span>
    <span class="pl-c"><span class="pl-c">#</span> now we can fallback if the first match fails</span>
	sed -rn <span class="pl-s"><span class="pl-pds">"</span><span class="pl-smi">$s</span><span class="pl-pds">"</span></span> <span class="pl-s"><span class="pl-pds">"</span><span class="pl-smi">$1</span><span class="pl-pds">"</span></span> <span class="pl-k">||</span> sed -rn <span class="pl-s"><span class="pl-pds">"</span><span class="pl-smi">$s</span><span class="pl-pds">"</span></span> <span class="pl-s"><span class="pl-pds">"</span><span class="pl-smi">$HEADER_MD</span><span class="pl-pds">"</span></span>
}</pre></div>
<p>Since <code>sed</code> doesn't have a return code of <code>1</code> when there is no match, you have
to do a little trick using <code>/matchRegex/s command/options</code> instead of the
traditional <code>s/find/replace/options</code>.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>My Return to a Custom Neovim Config</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/neovim_2024.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/neovim_2024.html</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 11:37:32 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">My Return to a Custom Neovim Config</h1><a id="user-content-my-return-to-a-custom-neovim-config" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: My Return to a Custom Neovim Config" href="#my-return-to-a-custom-neovim-config"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>At the end of 2023 I got antsy. I was finally going to do it...again. I was
about to venture on leaving <a href="https://github.com/LazyVim/LazyVim">LazyVim</a> and
create my own Neovim config from scratch using lazy.nvim with inspiration and
knowledge that I gathered from LazyVim (the greatest Neovim distro to date).</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">My Vim Journey</h2><a id="user-content-my-vim-journey" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: My Vim Journey" href="#my-vim-journey"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>My first exposure to vi/vim was after I installed Linux and needed to edit
files in the terminal, much like how other people probably find it. I don't
exactly remember if Ubuntu (my first distro) had Nano enabled as the default
editor back then, so I think I may have been forced to learn how to edit using
vi.</p>
<p>I slowly became comfortable editing files using Vim and even doing a little C
programming with it, but barely scratching the surface of the editor's power.</p>
<p>Once I got into Linux ricing, I saw that people had really cool looking Vim
configurations. I wanted to make mine look like that too, but I wasn't really
interested in using the editor for more than editing system files quickly.</p>
<p>Some time went by and I was finally sick of GUI editors being memory hogs and
slow. I went down the road of trying to configure Vim as a full-fledged IDE
using CoC and other great plugins from Tpope. I used that for a bit, but
couldn't really dive into using it permanently at work. It was still fun to
mess with in my free time.</p>
<p>One day I heard about Neovim and how it was supposedly <em>blazingly fast</em> with
LuaJIT and a faster development cycle. I installed and went down the road of
migrating over to a Lua-based config. It was early in the plugin days, so
things were really rough unless you had your ear to the ground and were already
a Vim/Lua wiz. I was not, so I got a bit overwhelmed.</p>
<p>This is about the time that I found out about Neovim distributions. It was a
relief from the anxiety of having to maintain my own configuration...or at
least I thought. Now instead of having to fix a plugin issue, I had to fix a
distro issue, wait for a fix to get pushed upstream, or disable a plugin that
they had added. After using my own config again for a bit, I settled on
AstroNvim, which was a pleasure to use at my job for a while.</p>
<p>Then lazy.nvim was released - a neovim package manager that was supposed to end
the problem of breaking configurations. Shortly after, lazy.nvim's creator and
Lua plugin warrior, <a href="https://github.com/folke">Folke</a> created LazyVim, a distro
that utilizes lazy.nvim. I immediately installed it and replaced AstroNvim. I
had been using it full-time up until about a week ago.</p>
<p>I began to get a bit frustrated again with using a distro after I got hit with
a few breaking changes, since I cannot resist updating all the plugins whenever
I see there are updates available. Things would break at the beginning of a
workday and I was too stubborn to rollback, so I neurotically would start
fixing editor issues instead of working.</p>
<p><em>Secretly switched to <a href="https://github.com/doomemacs/doomemacs">Doom Emacs</a> for a
bit</em></p>
<p>I came to the realization that I had no idea what was going on with my editor
anymore. I already forgot most of the stuff I learned from doing a custom
config last time (probably never learned it and copy pasted too much). It was
time to buckle down and start over.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Requirements</h3><a id="user-content-requirements" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Requirements" href="#requirements"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I made a list of the things that I truly needed to be productive in my editor:</p>
<ul>
<li>time</li>
<li>LSP</li>
<li>autocompletion</li>
<li>formatting</li>
<li>treesitter</li>
<li>statusbar</li>
<li>git integration</li>
<li>file tree</li>
<li>keybindings</li>
<li>all plugins and options that I curated using LazyVim</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Config Creation Workflow</h3><a id="user-content-config-creation-workflow" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Config Creation Workflow" href="#config-creation-workflow"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>In my opinion, getting keybindings, LSP and autocompletion working are the main
steps to a productive configuration. Basically, I started by reading
lazy.nvim's docs and hitting each of the requirements above, reading through
the docs of the plugins and sifting through Github discussions and issues when
I ran into a problem. Like I said, a lot of my config is taken from LazyVim,
because I believe it does the bulk of things in the ideal way. I spent a lot of
time reading through the LazyVim source code, then deciding if I needed to
extract certain things or could do it myself in a simpler way. I wanted to stay
minimalist so that when I read the configuration months down the
line I understand what is going on.</p>
<p>After that it is the grind of reading plugin docs and figuring out what you
need configured - a daunting task for newcomers and those who don't have the
time or patience to read docs.</p>
<p>I will still be following LazyVim's development because it has become somewhat
of a source of truth and the community is still active (even though as I write
this the project hasn't had a push for two months...)</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/trevarj/config.nvim">My 2024 Neovim Config</a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>The Open Source Influencer</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/OSS_influencer.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/OSS_influencer.html</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:46:15 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">The Open Source Influencer</h1><a id="user-content-the-open-source-influencer" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: The Open Source Influencer" href="#the-open-source-influencer"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I've been interested in tech content creation recently and have been trying to
guess the future of this modern programming career path. I'm constantly
intrigued by devs who are able to escape wage slave jobs and become self
sufficient somehow, whether it is by starting a business (the old way) or the
new ways of social media influencing or content creation. Creating a software
company definitely seems to be much harder nowadays in software than it was,
say, 10-15 years ago, and A LOT less enjoyable than the scenarios I present
below.</p>
<p>Since Github is now a social media site where you can even <a href="https://github.com/trending/developers">look up developers
by their popularity</a>, is it possible
that this will become a future career path in programming, just as Youtuber
became a career path for acting/comedy/cook/whatever else?</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Scenarios</h2><a id="user-content-scenarios" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Scenarios" href="#scenarios"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">1. Open Source Guru</h3><a id="user-content-1-open-source-guru" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: 1. Open Source Guru" href="#1-open-source-guru"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ol>
<li>Be a <a href="https://www.quora.com/Where-did-the-myth-of-the-10x-software-developer-come-from" rel="nofollow">10X
dev</a>
or expert in some area</li>
<li>Create or contribute to useful projects project(s)</li>
<li>Market project (or have followers/contributors do it) on social media</li>
<li>Start writing blogs, streaming, and/or making videos about that content and
more. Optional because these guys are good enough to just get picked up by a
top company.</li>
</ol>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">2. Twitch Programmer</h3><a id="user-content-2-twitch-programmer" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: 2. Twitch Programmer" href="#2-twitch-programmer"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ol>
<li>Be entertaining</li>
<li>Make tech videos or stream</li>
<li>Gather a following and sponsors</li>
<li>Create project on video or stream</li>
<li>Use following to boost project</li>
<li>Start selling stuff</li>
</ol>
<p>These scenarios could lead to the opportunity of quitting your day job and
starting to earn an income from donations or sponsorships (GH, Patreon, etc). It
seems like a nerdy version of a beauty blogger teaching how to put on makeup and
then pushing a cosmetic line...or an artist who streams painting and then sells
their works to viewers ...or even a battle worn veteran who tells war stories of
how he killed a bunch of really bad dudes and then starts a coffee company or
something...I don't know!</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Influence</h2><a id="user-content-influence" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Influence" href="#influence"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I'm not entirely sure how I feel about the influence these content creators have
on young programmers. I have certain opinions about the format in which the
content is delivered. For example, if done incorrectly, a stream can be a huge
waste of time for the viewer, even if it is entertaining. Maybe no one wants to
admit that though and would say that the engagement factor is important for
learning.</p>
<p>Will young programmers want to just become a tech influencer instead of putting
in the time working a terrible office job at least once like the rest of us? My
guess is not on a large scale like with regular social media, since programmers
tend to keep to themselves and be less outgoing.</p>
<p>Another thing that I think about is how these tech influencers are...influencers
in the sense that they can be idolized, which in turn can make product (courses,
merch, promo codes, etc) sales predatory, similar to what it's like on non-tech
social media.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">A Realistic Scenario</h2><a id="user-content-a-realistic-scenario" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: A Realistic Scenario" href="#a-realistic-scenario"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Obviously, the second scenario is not exactly probable or possible for everyone
to do.</p>
<p>I speculate that the first scenario can become more mainstream in the future, at
least for a seasoned developer (10+ years, or 10Xer) who prefers to not be in
the death grip of a software company. I suppose this scenario is analogous to
being a contractor and accepting a grant to work on an open source project that
you like, but with the addition of having individuals as supplemental
sponsorships. Basically, you're working on something you're passionate about and
people throw money at you for it.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Tech Influencer Network</h2><a id="user-content-tech-influencer-network" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Tech Influencer Network" href="#tech-influencer-network"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>A tech influencer from Scenario 1 or 2 builds his brand and decides to convert
into an organization. Other devs are hired and work on the org's projects, and
they can even champion their own projects and get marketed through the main
influencer's clout. You can see this in a lot of popular podcast networks and
other Youtuber channels. I'm pretty sure this already exists among tech
streamers, but I haven't looked into it much. It seems like it could be a nice
boost to open source development. I could be completely wrong though and someone
would point out all the reasons why this is a bad business model.</p>
<p>I don't know what the heck I'm talking about.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>Pre-Guix System Install Thoughts</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/Pre-Guix_System_Install_Thoughts.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/Pre-Guix_System_Install_Thoughts.html</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 16:55:59 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">Pre-Guix System Install Thoughts</h1><a id="user-content-pre-guix-system-install-thoughts" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Pre-Guix System Install Thoughts" href="#pre-guix-system-install-thoughts"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Ok, listen. I said a few posts back that I wasn't going to distrohop again after
Gentoo, but I lied. I just purchased a new Stinkpad, and I am going to give GNU
Guix System a shot.</p>
<p>It's an AMD machine, so there should be no need for any Nvidia hassle. In my
mind, it will go smoothly!</p>
<p>I'm making a public statement to hold myself accountable -- I shall give Guix a
fair try, attempt to make some contributions (if they'll have me!), and enjoy
helping others in the community as a bit of a hobby that will live safely on its
own hardware.</p>
<p>If it's really really bad, then I will just install FreeBSD or Debian, as
promised.</p>
<p>OR....</p>
<p>Maybe I will just embrace doing computing "the olds cool" way and have
everything broken, start smoking cigarettes at the keyboard, and doing a bit of
online gambling!</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>Some Thoughts on the Crypto Industry</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/Quick_Thought_on_Cryptocurrency_Technology.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/Quick_Thought_on_Cryptocurrency_Technology.html</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 10:35:54 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">Some Thoughts on the Crypto Industry</h1><a id="user-content-some-thoughts-on-the-crypto-industry" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Some Thoughts on the Crypto Industry" href="#some-thoughts-on-the-crypto-industry"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I've been working closely with numerous cryptocurrencies over the past four
years and I cannot get past an observation (maybe limited by my own perception)
of the industry and its technology.</p>
<p>I will state that I am not anti-crypto, per se, but I am anti-whatever I am
about to describe. I think crypto can provide a useful utility for people,
namely transferring funds elecronically without an intermediary (kinda). Do I
think the world would be worse without crypto? Not really. I am content with
Bitcoin and Ethereum, but beyond those I have not actually found a coin that
offers "life-improving" technology.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">The Technology</h2><a id="user-content-the-technology" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: The Technology" href="#the-technology"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I am going to completely generalize here, so take it with a grain of salt. Keep
in mind that I am a "nothing-to-show" dev who hasn't created such "successful"
projects before.</p>
<p>After reading through and working with many crypto projects, there are
practically none that seem impressive anymore. They are either poorly
documented, hastily written, over-engineered or just faulty. Rarely do they
promise something life-changing or revolutionary, no matter how much they hype
it up on social media. With confidence I can say that the majority of them are
just purely copy-pasted code and ideas that add one extra feature in hopes of
securing a voluptuous cash grab.</p>
<p>It's gotten to the point where it's laughable to me when a new crypto project
appears and it's just a fork of Ethereum or some other code with a few changes
added and a shiny, new website with some marketing.</p>
<p>Sometimes I think of all the code written for these projects and man-hours
wasted. It's comical, actually, especially since the code is just re-written
over and over or just abandonware at the end! This may be an issue with the
software industry as a whole, but it's amplified here.</p>
<p>Compare these types of projects with real engineering marvels, like a bridge or
a skyscraper, or even a missile launcher that will end up blowing up some
hospital far far away. Where is the utility in GooberCoin? Where is the
longevity? It's nowhere to be found, because it doesn't actually matter -- it's
FakeTech and it exists on web5 only.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Money and Tech Obsession</h2><a id="user-content-money-and-tech-obsession" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Money and Tech Obsession" href="#money-and-tech-obsession"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>Here are the most extreme archetypes of people in the crypto industry: those
obsessed with money, and those obsessed with technology. Probably sometimes
both. This may also apply to all industries, but I can see it very clearly here.</p>
<p>The person obsessed with money is an opportunist who wants to use technology to
lure in investors (big and small). They want the end product as fast as possible
so that the money flows in and the project says relevant. They will claim that
the project provides something more or is revolutionary. For the record, I don't
have anything against someone earning a lot of money through business, but it
appears to me that these projects are commonly deceptive and don't actually
provide anything useful (and sometimes don't even work well!). They will tell
you that these projects boost the entire industry as a whole and that they're
all working towards a common goal, yada yada...</p>
<p>The person obsessed with technology is intelligent, but how I see it,
unwise. They want to implement the latest findings in mathematics, cryptography,
networking, computer science, etc, but without truly contemplating the question
"is this work necessary or beneficial for society?". The amount of funds in the
crypto industry allows this to be possible. The technologist, investors and
end-user are all feeding off of each other. They all love extremely complicated
systems that are almost esoteric, when all we probably need is something simple
that serves a good purpose and does it well.</p>
<p>Take the latest paper in cryptography and implement it, then generate a surplus
of "coins" attached to this technology, and then sell it to people who want to
enjoy the benefits of snake oil and get RICH! Done!</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
<title>Ten Years a Dev</title>
<guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/ten_years.html</guid>
<link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/ten_years.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="markdown-heading"><h1 class="heading-element">Ten Years a Dev</h1><a id="user-content-ten-years-a-dev" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Ten Years a Dev" href="#ten-years-a-dev"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Introduction</h2><a id="user-content-introduction" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Introduction" href="#introduction"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>This year will mark my tenth year working as a professional software engineer.
Lately, I have been contemplating on my experience and my next steps and goals
that I would like to achieve as a programmer. I also want to be sure that I
don't fall into the same traps as I did before.</p>
<p>#This post is intended as notes for my future-self.# Hopefully this will help
me organize my thoughts on what to do in the next ten years.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">First Job (Spring 2013)</h2><a id="user-content-first-job-spring-2013" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: First Job (Spring 2013)" href="#first-job-spring-2013"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Positives</h3><a id="user-content-positives" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Positives" href="#positives"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Had a mentor</li>
<li>Exposed to low level programming</li>
<li>Learned about GNU/Linux for ARM, custom SBCs</li>
<li>R&amp;D experience</li>
<li>Fun coworkers</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Negatives</h3><a id="user-content-negatives" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Negatives" href="#negatives"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Project stagnated</li>
<li>Didn't write enough C or learn as much about hardware as I should have</li>
<li>Long commute</li>
<li>Left job early for Java money and short commute</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Reasons for Joining</h3><a id="user-content-reasons-for-joining" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Reasons for Joining" href="#reasons-for-joining"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Recommended by a professor from university</li>
<li>Interested in low-level programming and hardware</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Reasons for Leaving</h3><a id="user-content-reasons-for-leaving" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Reasons for Leaving" href="#reasons-for-leaving"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Bored and felt like I couldn't learn more from the job</li>
<li>Commute was annoying</li>
<li>Others were thinking about leaving and one guy already left</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Second Job (Summer 2014)</h2><a id="user-content-second-job-summer-2014" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Second Job (Summer 2014)" href="#second-job-summer-2014"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Positives</h3><a id="user-content-positives-1" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Positives" href="#positives-1"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Became comfortable in large, legacy codebase</li>
<li>Experienced full-stack for a while</li>
<li>Lots of debugging and learned to hunt bugs</li>
<li>Multiple salary increases</li>
<li>Went full-remote (pre-C#vid, remote hipster)</li>
<li>Fun coworkers</li>
<li>Five minutes from home and personal freedom</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Negatives</h3><a id="user-content-negatives-1" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Negatives" href="#negatives-1"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Got stuck in legacy code Java 8 hell</li>
<li>Didn't focus on career growth enough</li>
<li>Stayed way too long</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Reasons for Joining</h3><a id="user-content-reasons-for-joining-1" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Reasons for Joining" href="#reasons-for-joining-1"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Bought into the mission</li>
<li>Seemed like there was room for growth</li>
<li>Close to home</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Reasons for Leaving</h3><a id="user-content-reasons-for-leaving-1" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Reasons for Leaving" href="#reasons-for-leaving-1"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Corporate takeover consequences (relocate or take pay cut)</li>
<li>Tired of Java 8, legacy code and product</li>
<li>Felt like my programming skills were atrophying</li>
<li>Agile is so annoying and never done well</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Third Job (Fall 2020)</h2><a id="user-content-third-job-fall-2020" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Third Job (Fall 2020)" href="#third-job-fall-2020"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>!! Will update later !!</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Positives</h3><a id="user-content-positives-2" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Positives" href="#positives-2"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Fully Rust codebase</li>
<li>New project when I joined</li>
<li>Great teammates</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Negatives</h3><a id="user-content-negatives-2" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Negatives" href="#negatives-2"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>
</li></ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Reasons for Joining</h3><a id="user-content-reasons-for-joining-2" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Reasons for Joining" href="#reasons-for-joining-2"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<ul>
<li>Wanted to program Rust full-time</li>
<li>Interested in the company's industry</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Reasons for Leaving</h3><a id="user-content-reasons-for-leaving-2" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Reasons for Leaving" href="#reasons-for-leaving-2"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>N/A</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Conclusions</h2><a id="user-content-conclusions" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Conclusions" href="#conclusions"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>After ten years, I hoped that I would be a bit more advanced with programming
and not a general application developer. I regret not using my young buck energy
and brain to learn a specific domain or pursue a master's degree to study a
topic deeply. I've always been fascinated by advanced CS/programming topics like
compilers and operating systems, but have had trouble self-learning them. This
makes me wonder if I even have a strong enough passion for programming and
computer science to go beyond application development.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h3 class="heading-element">Bipolar Statements</h3><a id="user-content-bipolar-statements" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Bipolar Statements" href="#bipolar-statements"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>I am extremely grateful to be a programmer during this time period, getting into
the industry when jobs are aplenty, and earning more than enough to live a very
comfortable life. Being able to work from anywhere, at any time of the day is a
luxury that almost all professions lack.</p>
<p>I wish someone told me ten years ago that most of professional programming, and
maybe software in general nowadays, kind of sucks and you will most likely be
working on a product that you don't use or isn't yours and that will turn into a
disgusting mess due to business people getting their hands involved in
technology and prioritizing profits and timelines over anything else.</p>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Side Projects</h2><a id="user-content-side-projects" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Side Projects" href="#side-projects"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>These are computer-related things that I pursued and will continue to pursue outside
of work:</p>
<ul>
<li>Contributing to and writing open source software</li>
<li>Daily driving Unix-like operating systems and configuring them for fun</li>
<li>Learned Rust, Haskell, Idris, and tinkered with other various languages</li>
<li>Participating in IRC to learn and help others</li>
<li>Refining my development environment and workflow</li>
<li>Tinkering, writing simple programs, tools, and games</li>
<li>Trying to brush up on and learn other CS topics</li>
</ul>
<div class="markdown-heading"><h2 class="heading-element">Goals</h2><a id="user-content-goals" class="anchor" aria-label="Permalink: Goals" href="#goals"><span aria-hidden="true" class="octicon octicon-link"/></a></div>
<p>The following are goals that I would like to achieve in the next ten years.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>years</th>
<th>goal</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 2</td>
<td>Write more C; at a job or more personal projects.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 5</td>
<td>Do a project for OS dev; write a shell, bootloader, Forth, etc.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 5</td>
<td>Make code contributions to a large open source project - a feature or bugfix.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 5</td>
<td>Do a project with an embedded device.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 5</td>
<td>Reduce time spent on the computer in freetime.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 5</td>
<td>Find job in specialized field instead of app dev.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 10</td>
<td>Get paid to work on open source software full time.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt;= 10</td>
<td>Be self-employed.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>= 10</td>
<td>Retire...PLEASE</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>