<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opinion on Trevor Arjeski's Site</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in opinion on Trevor Arjeski's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Trevor Arjeski</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 19:33:07 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trevarj.github.io/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Late Start in Computer Programming</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/advice2noob/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 19:33:07 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/advice2noob/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving advice (sometimes unsolicited) to people who want to shift into computer programming as a career.
Being a late bloomer in programming is definitely manageable, but I believe it requires careful planning and a specific behavior.
Overview This has been beaten like a dead horse by #learn2code tweets and Youtube videos, but these are the two main goals to become a general application programmer:
Learn the fundamentals of programming and the basics of how a computer works Learn one programming language and write programs in it Contribute to open source projects and/or have a personal project Behavior The most difficult undertaking and, what I think, is the most important factor for learning programming is the obsession needed to succeed.</description></item><item><title>The If-Else Programmer</title><link>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/if_else/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trevarj.github.io/posts/if_else/</guid><description>I had a half-joke where I would tell people that all I did at a previous job was write if-else statements to fix every problem that came up. There are two reasons why I evolved into the if-else programmer:
Ideas and creativity were ignored. Anything a developer offered to improve the code was rejected and deemed as not needed by management. The value was only found in things that instantly settled client demands.</description></item></channel></rss>